Timothy Michael Keller 6501 21st Ave. NW Seattle, WA 98117 Timothy.M.Keller@gmail.com (206) 353-9625

Summary:

Full-stack web developer specializing in front-end design and development. Experienced with multiple CMS and all stages of development and design of dynamic websites and web apps. Knowledgeable in all critical front-end development programming languages with a strong background in several back-end languages.

Experience:

Web Developer Freelance

2012 - present

- Led a small team of graphic designers to quickly deliver high-quality frontend websites.
- Work closely with clients to create specific, custom-tailored web design solutions for businesses.
- Complete detail-oriented programming and scripting projects for front-end sites, and complicated clean code for back-end work.
- Execute painstaking bug-testing to ensure an error-free product.
- Actively promoted "win-win" client interactions to ensure a positive experience both for employees and the client.

Web Developer Dovie.tv/BuildYourStoreOnline 2013 - present

- Sat in on and participated in client meetings to fully grasp project scope and client wishes.
- Worked closely with project managers to optimize workflow and eliminate errors from poor communication.
- Participated in scheduling of deadlines and project milestones.
- Accepted difficult projects to build skills and discipline.
- Singlehandedly built highly complex WordPress sites using custom PHP code.
- Debugged and modified existing sites built by the organization.
- Created custom WordPress themes for clients, including a site generating a four-figure passive income for a client and sites that dramatically improved clients' workflow and efficiency.

Web Developer Atoms & Pixels

2016 - 2018

- Interacted directly with clients to formulate a list of needs and requirements for site builds.
- Led and advised a small team of data entry clerks. Delivered goals consistently on-time and under budget.
- Formulated deadlines and project milestones in conjunction with project lead.
- Repaired code on buggy systems.
- Diagnosed and fixed software conflicts.
- Coordinated large-scale automated data entry systems and moved large amounts of database data from server to server.
- Singlehandedly built and configured client sites built in multiple programming languages and across multiple CMSes.

Education:

Bachelor of Arts: Music Graduated 2008 University of Washington

12-Week Web Development Bootcamp Graduated March 2020 University of Washington

Coursera Courses:

Linear Algebra Machine Learning

PSI Seminars:

Basic seminar PSI 7 Men's Leadership Seminar

Programming Languages, Frameworks, and CMS:

HTML, CSS, PHP, Javascript, Python, SQL, Java, SuperCollider Bootstrap, JQuery, React, MongoDB

WordPress, Drupal, Magento, Joomla, Shopify, AWS

Personal References:

Dayvin Turchiano (Owner, BuildYourStoreOnline.com/Dovie.tv)
dayvin@buildyourstoreonline.com
(541) 324-8120

Dr. Philip Snell, DC (Owner, MyRehabExercise.com) drphillipsnell@gmail.com (503) 957-7926

Notable Projects:

- Weather Dashboard with OpenWeatherMap API: Dashboard for weather forecasts built with Javascript and JQuery, using OpenWeatherMap's free API to build custom 5-day forecasts and current weather displays based on user city input.
 - **URL**: https://github.com/tmkeller/weather-dashboard
- Voicely Voice-Activated Texting and Note-Taking App: Group project for University of Washington's coding bootcamp. Voicely is a voice-activated texting and note-taking app that features speech-to-text via Microsoft's Speech SDK, texting via the ClickSend API, and speech-activated emojis via the Emoji API. Written in HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Vanilla Javascript, and using Google's Materialize library. I was personally responsible for contributions across the tech stack, but focused mostly on parsing responses from the speech SDK to create custom characters using voice commands.

URL: https://github.com/chomieu/Project-1/

Online Portfolio: Vanilla CSS and HTML.
 URL: https://tmkeller.github.io/hw-02-responsive-portfolio/